Kick Some Asteroid.
Ratchet & Clank is a action, adventure, animation
film directed by Jericca Cleland.
When the galaxy comes under the threat of a nefarious space captain, a mechanic and his
newfound robot ally join an elite squad of combatants to save the universe.
Ratchet (voice), played by James Arnold Taylor.
Clank (voice), played by David Kaye.
Captain Qwark (voice), played by Jim Ward.
Chairman Drek (voice), played by Paul Giamatti.
Dr. Nefarious (voice), played by Armin Shimerman.
Elaris (voice), played by Rosario Dawson.
Ratchet & Clank is a 2016 animated science fiction comedy film based on the
Insomniac Games video game series, and directed by Kevin Munroe.
James Arnold Taylor and David Kaye reprise their roles as the titular characters from the video
games, alongside Jim Ward and Armin Shimerman as their respective characters.
The film also stars the voices of Paul Giamatti, John Goodman,
Bella Thorne, Rosario Dawson, and Sylvester Stallone.
The film features an original story, loosely based on the 2002 video game with additional elements from
its follow-ups, written by Munroe, Gerry Swallow, and former Insomniac senior writer T.J.
Fixman, who began writing for the series with the Ratchet & Clank Future saga.
Alongside several cast members from the games, Insomniac contributed to the film's
production with character development, screenplay, and animation assets.
Released in the United States on April 29, 2016, Ratchet & Clank received negative
reviews and grossed $14 million worldwide on a $20 million budget.
It is the final film by Gramercy Pictures as a label before it was
discontinued the second time shortly thereafter.
It also ended up being Gramercy's only animated film.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, saving the world,
extraterrestrial technology, villain, alien.